Guide to the William O. Douglas Collection 1920-1980
Whitman College and Northwest Archives
William O. Douglas Collection
1920-1980 (bulk 1939-1975)
Whitman College and Northwest Archives 345 Boyer Avenue Walla Walla, WA 99362 (509) 527-5922 archives@whitman.edu http://www.whitman.edu/archives
HTM_WCMss48
Douglas, William O. (William Orville) 1898-1980
26 linear feet 27 boxes, 1 oversize box, 1 scrapbook, 4 binders
The William O. Douglas Collection contains the former Supreme Court Justice’s research materials, reports to Congress, book manuscripts, published articles, law practice records, correspondence with friends and associates, and materials relating to his association with Whitman College.
Biographical Note
Douglas was born in Maine Township, Minnesota. His family moved to California, and then Cleveland, Washington. His father died in Portland, Oregon in 1904, when he was only six years old. In 1916, Douglas won a scholarship to Whitman College in Walla Walla, Washington. He taught at Yakima High School for two years before attending Yale Law School, graduating in 1925. After practicing law and teaching at Yale, he joined the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission, becoming Chairman in 1937. He finally was appointed by President Franklin D. Roosevelt to the Supreme Court in 1939.
During his tenure on the bench, Justice Douglas achieved a number of records and distinctions. Along with the longevity record, he also established the records for the most opinions written, the most dissents written, the most speeches given, and the most books authored by any member of the Supreme Court. He also achieved a few less savory records, such as the most wives (four), the most divorces while on the bench (three), and the most attempts at impeachment (three). None of these records have been surpassed.
The William O. Douglas Collection includes speeches, research materials, correspondence, postcards, forestry management, reports to Congress, invitations, book manuscripts, publications, newspaper clippings, contracts, law practice records, articles and magazines about conservation, correspondence with Len Jansen, and materials collected by Whitman College staff.
By series.
None.
Donated to the Whitman College and Northwest Archives by Leonard F. Jansen, 1995; additional material donated by David Danelski in 1998; material collected by Whitman College.
Douglas, William Orville -- Archives.
United States Supreme Court
Civil Procedure and Courts
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Papers created and collected by Douglas, Series 1; 21 boxes
  - Credo/Future Speech file, 1940-1972; Sub-Series 1
    Newspaper and other published articles used by Douglas filed by subject matter.
    - Africa: South Africa, Congo, Algeria, ect. news clippings (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Africa: Congo and South West Africa news clippings (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Africa: Wild life, Chad, Congo information books (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Agriculture clippings and pamphlet (Box-folder 1/4)
    - The Agricultual Unionist (Box-folder 1/5)
    - American History magazines and booklets (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Cambodia and Thailand bulletin (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Artistic and Literary Freedom in USSR (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Australia cardboard Ab-original poster (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Censorship (movies in US, press Australia) (Box-folder 1/10)
    - China: magazines on medicine, art and communism (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Civil Rights (US) desegregation news clippings and booklet (Box-folder 1/12)
    - Cold War (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Colleges: clippings and Yale magazine (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Commission on Judicial and Congressional Recommendations (Box-folder 1/15)
    - Community Projects/ Services (Box-folder 1/16)
    - Communism (general): magazines, clippings, booklets (Box-folder 1/17)
    - Comparative history (Roman and American) (Box-folder 1/18)
    - Conservation (Box-folder 1/19)
    - Corporate Mergers/ Anti Trust (Box-folder 1/20)
    - Courts: Warren Says Congestion in Courts Rises (Box-folder 1/20.5)
    - Cuba: Foreign papers and magazine articles (Box-folder 1/21)
    - Cuba: Editorials and Commentary on Missle Crisis (Box-folder 1/22)
    - Cuba, US, and USSR news clippings (Box-folder 1/23)
    - Cuba: Weapons, bases news clippings (Box-folder 1/24)
    - Department of Labor, State Unemployment Laws (Box-folder 1/25)
    - Eastern Europe: Yugoslovia (Box-folder 1/26)
    - Education (Box-folder 1/27)
    - FDR 3rd Inaugural Address and Service (Box-folder 1/28)
    - 5th Amendment (Box-folder 1/29)
    - Foreign Aid news clippings (Box-folder 1/30)
    - Free Speech in Pakistan (Box-folder 1/31)
    - Foreign Policy clippings and booklets (Box-folder 1/32)
    - Function of the Military (Box-folder 1/33)
    - Government and the Press (Box-folder 1/34)
    - (Harvard) College Loyalty Upheld by Pusey (Box-folder 1/34.5)
    - Health/ WHO (Box-folder 1/35)
    - History (US) (Box-folder 1/36)
    - History of Drug Control (Box-folder 1/36.5)
    - India (Box-folder 1/37)
    - India and China Conflict (1962), India and Gao, Nehru (Box-folder 1/38)
    - Intolerance in America (Box-folder 1/39)
    - Economic Problems of Free Japan (Box-folder 1/40)
    - Full Force of Martial Law will be used: Mischieveous Misuse of Questionnaire: CMLA HQ's Press Note (Box-folder 1/41)
    - The Nation of Islam- Black Muslins (Box-folder 1/42)
    - Reflections: The New Justice: New Yorker (Box-folder 1/43)
    - Korea (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Laos news clippings (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Law Articles and Journals (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Law Articles and Reviews (Connected with a University) (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Legislative Investigations (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Facts about Maine (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Malaysia news clippings (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Materials for Unwritten Book (Asia news clippings) (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Memorial/ Obituary: Robert G. Lindsay (Box-folder 2/9)
    - Mexico and California: Agriculture and Workers (Box-folder 2/10)
    - Middle East: clippings and magazines (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Middle East: clippings (Box-folder 2/12)
    - Misc. clippings (Box-folder 2/13)
    - Jean Monnet (1962 Freedom Award) (Box-folder 2/14)
    - NATO (Box-folder 2/15)
    - Nation of Islam (Box-folder 2/16)
    - 1941 Unity for Defense/ Military build up (Box-folder 2/17)
    - Non Mainstream Political Groups (Box-folder 2/18)
    - Non Violence (Box-folder 2/19)
    - Nuclear Arms Race/ Nuclear Testing (Box-folder 2/20)
    - Nuclear Issues: General, Health Hazards, Other Dangers (Box-folder 2/21)
    - Observer: The Alameda County Weekly (Box-folder 2/22)
    - Pakistan news clippings (Box-folder 2/23)
    - The Palestine Refugee Problem (Box-folder 2/24)
    - Phillippines magazines (Box-folder 2/25)
    - Philosophy/ History/ Technology (Box-folder 2/26)
    - Political Cartoons (Box-folder 2/27)
    - Political Commentary clippings and World Liberation publication (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Political Speeches: Dewey's annual message to legislature, Eisenhower's press conference (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Politics: -- Lemmings (Box-folder 3/2.5)
    - Population and Overpopulation publication and census report (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Poverty and Hunger clippings and feature stories (Box-folder 3/4)
    - US Red Scare, McCarthyism and foreign service clippings (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Religion: The Pope Speaks and other publications (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Religion: clippings from the Christian Science Monitor and other publications (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Religious Issue: Pressures on Catholic President (JFK) (Box-folder 3/7.5)
    - Russia clippings (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Scientific Exploration/ Need for new Knowledge (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Security and Secrecy in Science, Oppenheimer Case (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Socialism, Fortune:Churchill piece (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Southeast Asia (Box-folder 3/12)
    - Vital Speeches (publication) and speech announcement (Box-folder 3/13)
    - Struggles between branches of US government (Box-folder 3/14)
    - Supreme Court (Box-folder 3/15)
    - Trade, Common Market, GATT, French-German Treaty (Box-folder 3/16)
    - Turkey: The Institute of Public Affairs (Box-folder 3/17)
    - United Nations clippings and magazines (Box-folder 3/18)
    - US Economy: clippings, brochures, magazines (Box-folder 3/19)
    - US Defense: Christian Science Monitor article (Box-folder 3/20)
    - US Politics: War, elections, House information (Box-folder 3/21)
    - US Propoganda: Overseas information programs documents (Box-folder 3/22)
    - US, USSR re. Space (Box-folder 3/23)
    - Court clippings (Box-folder 3/24)
    - Vietnam clippings (Box-folder 3/25)
    - Welfare, Federal Housing, Child Labor (Box-folder 3/26)
    - Western Europe: Switzerland, France documents (Box-folder 3/27)
    - Work on Self-Expression (Box-folder 3/27.5)
    - World Economy, Common Markets, Resources (Box-folder 3/28)
    - World Peace, Turning Point Toward Peace (publication), brochure (Box-folder 3/29)
  - Almanac of Liberty, Sub-Series 2
    A commentary on human rights that Douglas compiled based on key events in history.
    - Almanac of Liberty: Galley Proofs (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Almanac of Liberty: Introduction (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Almanac of Liberty: Interview at Studio One Television Program, New York (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Almanac of Liberty: Honesty and Morals in America (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Almanac of Liberty: Confidentiality Rights of Journalists "Right of Silence" (Box-folder 5/5)
    - Almanac of Liberty: Segregation/Civil Rights (Box-folder 5/6)
    - Almanac of Liberty: Civil Liberties (including wire tapping) File #1 (Box-folder 5/7)
    - Almanac of Liberty: Civil Liberties (including wire tapping) File #2 (Box-folder 5/8)
    - Almanac of Liberty: Fairness of the Press (Box-folder 5/9)
    - Almanac of Liberty: Monroe Doctrine (Box-folder 5/10)
    - Almanac of Liberty: General Politics (Box-folder 5/11)
    - Almanac of Liberty: Reviews (Box-folder 5/12)
    - Almanac of Liberty: McCarthyism, Communism and Subversion File #1 (Box-folder 5/13)
    - Almanac of Liberty: McCarthyism, Communism and Subversion File #2 (Box-folder 5/14)
    - Almanac of Liberty: McCarthyism, Communism and Subversion File #3 (Box-folder 5/15)
    - Almanac of Liberty: History, Monarchs, US, Supreme Court Justices etc. (Box-folder 5/16)
    - Almanac of Liberty: Slavery; Slavery in the Middle East, UN conference on abolition of slavery (Box-folder 5/17)
    - Almanac of Liberty: Atomic Energy and Bombs (Box-folder 5/18)
    - Almanac of Liberty: FCC (Box-folder 5/19)
    - Almanac of Liberty: Censorship, Book Burning and McCarthy (Box-folder 5/20)
    - Almanac of Liberty: Forward (Box-folder 5/21)
    - Almanac of Liberty: Misc. articles (Box-folder 5/22)
    - Postcards Concerning Rosenberg stay (copies) (Box-folder 5/23)
    - Rosenberg Telegrams (copies) Against Stay of Execution (Box-folder 5/24)
    - Rosenberg Telegrams (copies) For Stay of Execution (Box-folder 5/25)
    - Rosenberg Telegrams (copies) For Stay of Execution (Box-folder 5/26)
  - Special Correspondence and Invitations, 1937-1979; Sub-Series 3
    - Securities and Exchange Commission, December 1937-July 1938 (Box-folder 14/1)
    - Securities and Exchange Commission Telegrams, April 28, 1938-June 16, 1938 (Box-folder 14/2)
    - Special Correspondence: US Supreme Court, Undated (Box-folder 14/3)
    - Special Correspondence: Invitations to W.O.D., 1939-1955 (Box 15)
    - Family Correspondence, 1939-1975 (Box-folder 14/4)
    - Special Correspondence: Horse Accident, 1949 (Box-folder 14/5-13)
    - Request for Autograph, 1957-1971 (Box-folder 14/20-23)
    - Invitations to W.O.D., 1957-1979 (Box 19)
    - Special Correspondence: Hospitalization, 1968 (Box-folder 14/14-19)
    - Special Correspondence: Fan Mail, 1974 (Box-folder 14/24-27)
    - 14 Folders of Get Well Letters, Cards, Newspaper Articles Re: Stroke and Resignation Notice A-G, 1975 (Box 12)
    - 19 Folders of Get Well Letters, Cards, Newspaper Articles Re: Stroke and Resignation Notice H-Z, 1975 (Box 13)
  - Douglas Subject Files, Sub-Series 4
    Part 1: Adventuring-Conservation; Part 2: Misc. Materials on Conservation - Fishing; Part 3: Forestry Management, Reports to Congress; Part 4: Rivers - Yellowstone
    - Adventuring (Camping, Mountaineering, etc.) Explorer's Journals, Outdoor Club Pamphlets (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Africa: Wildlife Magazine vol.2 no.3 (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Alaska: (Conservation, Camping etc.) Pamphlets, Materials on Conserving Alaska (Box-folder 6/3)
    - Alaska Conservation Society News Bulletins (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Antarctic: Geographic Journal vol. 129 part I (Box-folder 6/5)
    - Appalachia Journals vol.26 no. 3; vol.27, no.3 (Box-folder 6/6)
    - Appalachian Mountain Club Materials (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Appalachia Journal, vol.26, no.1 (Box-folder 6/8)
    - Appalachia: Report by the President's Appalachian Regional Commission (Box-folder 6/9)
    - Pamphlets on Bills and Acts: Clean Air, est. Husdon Highlands National Scenic Riverway (Box-folder 6/10)
    - Buffalo National River: Field Investigation Report (Box-folder 6/11)
    - Guides, Journals and Pamphlets re: CO Canal (Box-folder 6/12)
    - California Sierras and Highway Plan and Parks Material (Box-folder 6/13)
    - Canada: Quetico Newsletters and Foundation (Box-folder 6/14)
    - Canada: Voyageur Magazine, Canoe Routes of the Voyageurs (Box-folder 6/15)
    - Material re: Washington Cascades (Box-folder 6/16)
    - US News and World Report: Why Cattle Prices are Low (Box-folder 6/17)
    - Congressional Records: Pesticide Hearings (Box-folder 6/18)
    - Conservation: Allegash (Proposed National Park) (Box-folder 6/19)
    - Conservation: Bodega Head (Box-folder 6/20)
    - Conservation: Cape Cod (Box-folder 6/21)
    - Conservation: Capitol Reef (Box-folder 6/22)
    - Misc. Conservation Club Newsletters (Box-folder 6/23)
    - Conservation: Cougar Lakes, WA. Pacific Northwest (Box-folder 6/24)
    - Conservation: Florida: Cross-State Barge Canal (Box-folder 6/25)
    - General Conservation Papers (Box-folder 6/26)
    - Conservation: Indiana Dunes (Box-folder 7/1)
    - Conservation: International (Box-folder 7/2)
    - Lake Tahoe (Box-folder 7/3)
    - Conservation: Minum Valley (Box-folder 7/4)
    - Counservation: Mount Vernon (Box-folder 7/5)
    - Conservation: National Parks and Forests (Box-folder 7/6)
    - Conservation: New York and New Jersey (Box-folder 7/7)
    - Conservation: Rainbow Bridge (Box-folder 7/8)
    - Conservation: San Gorgonio Wild Area (Box-folder 7/9)
    - Newspaper Articles on Various Dams (Box-folder 7/10)
    - Department of the Interior re: Wildlife (Box-folder 7/11)
    - Articles on Desalinization (Box-folder 7/12)
    - Misc. Guide Books, Articles on East Coast Wilderness #1 (Box-folder 7/13)
    - Misc. Guide Books, Articles on East Coast Wilderness #2 (Box-folder 7/14)
    - Economics of Retaining Open Spaces (Box-folder 7/15)
    - Pamphlet on Green Oaks, Knox College "Education" (Box-folder 7/16)
    - Newspaper Articles on Energy Sources (Box-folder 7/17)
    - Pamphlets on Virginian Farms (Box-folder 7/18)
    - Articles on Farming: "Green Revolution" (Box-folder 7/19)
    - Atlantic Naturalist Journal, 5 volumes, Misc. Naturalist Journals and Newsletters (Box-folder 7/20)
    - Fauna Magazine Articles (Box-folder 7/21)
    - Fauna: Misc. (Box-folder 7/22)
    - Fauna: Newspaper Clippings (Box-folder 7/23)
    - Various Publications and Journals re: Fauna (Box-folder 7/24)
    - Wildlife Review Journal, 4 volumes, 1 copy; Victoria, B.C. (Box-folder 7/25)
    - World Wildlife Fund Materials (Box-folder 7/26)
    - Articles and Journals on Fishing (Box-folder 7/27)
    - Materials on Forest Land Use and "Multiple Use Concept" (Box-folder 8/1)
    - Bureaucracy and the Forests, Public and Nation's Forests, A.W. Lafferty "Pours on the Coal" (Box-folder 8/2)
    - Misc. Newspaper Articles on Forest Multiple Use, Land Management Documents (Box-folder 8/3)
    - Material on the Great Smokies, Wildflower Guide, "Smokies Guide," Newspaper Article on New Highway (Box-folder 8/4)
    - Richard D. McCarthy Articles, Documents on Herbicides (Box-folder 8/5)
    - House of Representatives: Acts, Bills and Joint Resolutions re: Wilderness Management (Box-folder 8/6)
    - House of Representatives: Reports, Copies of Congressional record, US Court of Appeals re: Environment (Box-folder 8/7)
    - Oregon State Game Commission, Misc. Newspaper Articles re: Hunting (Box-folder 8/8)
    - Misc. Articles re: Lakes, Marshes, Swamps, Waterways. US Canoes Assoc. Newsletter vol. 2, no.3 (Box-folder 8/9)
    - Living Wilderness Journal: nos. 58, 78 (2 copies, 1 excerpt), 80,82,84 (Box-folder 8/10)
    - Articles on Vehicle Use in Trail Country (Box-folder 8/11)
    - Articles on Man's Connection to Nature (Box-folder 8/12)
    - Science Articles: DNA Heredity, Peant Mold, Antibiotics (Box-folder 8/13)
    - Materials on the Mid-West and Cleaning (Box-folder 8/14)
    - National Parks Magazine: August 1961, December 1962, January 1963, February 1964, March 1964, April 1966 (Box-folder 8/15)
    - National Grasslands Story. US Dept. of Agriculture (Box-folder 8/16)
    - National Parks Service Materials (Box-folder 8/17)
    - Newspaper Articles Regarding Native Americans: Iroquois, Virgin Islanders, Seminoles, Chinooks (Box-folder 8/18)
    - Nevada Proposed National Park: 2 maps, Great Basin Range (Box-folder 8/19)
    - Material on North Cascades Conservation Council: Newsletters (Box-folder 8/20)
    - North Cascades Conservation Council re: North Cascades National Park (Box-folder 8/21)
    - North Cascades Conservation Council: Photos of Proposed North Cascades National Park (Box-folder 8/22)
    - Articles on Nuclear Radiation, Nuclear Information Vol.III Nos. 4-7, I.F. Stone's Weekly Vols. 810 (Box-folder 8/23)
    - "The Olympic Seashore," Ruth Kirk, Western Outdoor Quarterly Vol. 26 No. 2 (Box-folder 8/24)
    - Materials on Pacific NW: Elgin, OR., Minam Lodge, LaPush Shipwreck Memorial Ruth Kirk (Box-folder 8/25)
    - Newspaper Articles/ Editorials on the Use of Pesticides/ The Backlog Vol. 37 No. 2 (Box-folder 8/26)
    - Materials on Pesticides (DDT, Agent Orange) and Their Effects on Humans/ Organic Gardening Farming (Box-folder 8/27)
    - Misc. Materials on Pesticides and Their Effects on the Natural World (Box-folder 8/28)
    - Misc. Plant Guides; Articles on Plant Life, Logging; Forest Service Handbook on Plant Collections (Box-folder 8/29)
    - Misc. Articles on Pollution (Box-folder 8/30)
    - Potomic Heritage Trail: A Proposed Trunk in a Nationwide System of Trails (2 Copies) (Box-folder 8/31)
    - Proposed Prairie Nat'l Park/ Proposed Allagash Nat'l Recreation Area (Box-folder 8/32)
    - Public Land Statistics 1963: US Dept. of the Interior (Box-folder 8/33)
    - Materials on Reservoirs: "Reservoirs: A Prospectus for Sport Fishery Research"/ Misc. Aricles (Box-folder 8/34)
    - Reports to Congress Regarding Pesticides, by the President's Science Advisory Committee (Box-folder 8/35)
    - Senate Reports, Acts, Hearings re: Environmental Laws/Concerns. Review of Taylor Grazing Act (Box-folder 9/1)
    - Senate Hearings RE. Insecticides and Land Preservation/ Congressional Record RE. Rivers System (Box-folder 9/2)
    - Articles, Journals, Reports RE. Potomac River et. al. (Box-folder 9/3)
    - Shoreline Management Act of 1971; WA State: The Lakes, Final Proposed Guidelines (Box-folder 9/4)
    - Sierra Club Bulletin: 5 Vols. The Argonaut; Sierra Club. (Box-folder 9/5)
    - Sierra Club Bulletin: 1937; 1957; In One Book: '66, '67, '68 (Box-folder 9/6)
    - Sierra Club Bulletin: November 1958, December 1956 (Box-folder 9/7)
    - Three Newspaper Articles on Smog: Nevada State Journal, Washington Post, NY Times Magazine (Box-folder 9/8)
    - Materials on Soil Conservation/ Erosion (Box-folder 9/9)
    - Amazon Journal (Belem): Regarding South American Wildlife/ Letter # 5 (Box-folder 9/10)
    - Materials on Coal Strip Mining in US: Articles, Reports, Journals (Box-folder 9/11)
    - Nature's Constant Gift,' Report and Article on the Tennessee Valley (Box-folder 9/12)
    - Misc. Materials on the Timber Industry/ Private Forestry (Box-folder 9/13)
    - Misc. Tourism Pamphlets/ Articles (Box-folder 9/14)
    - U.S. Forest Service (Regulations, Reports, Articles on) (Box-folder 9/15)
    - Materials on Virginia State Parks, White Water Rafting and 'Environment News' Vol. 3 No. 9-10 (Box-folder 9/16)
    - The Governor's Report on Outdoor Recreation in Washington (Box-folder 9/17)
    - Misc. Articles, Pamphlets on Water Conservation (Box-folder 9/18)
    - Misc. Articles, Materials on Water Pollution/ Ground Water Contamination (Box-folder 9/19)
    - Wyoming Federation of Sportsmen's Clubs/ Wyoming Conservation Assoc. Newsletters (Box-folder 9/20)
    - Articles Re. Powerboating on Yellowstone Lake (Box-folder 9/21)
    - Inventories: Libraries, Homes, Soundtracks, Reels, Undated (Box-folder 20/1)
    - Law: ABA, Record of Law Clerks, 1957 (Box-folder 20/2)
    - Memo: On the Ghashghai Problem, 1956 (Box-folder 20/3)
    - Writings: Travels (Political Situation in Far East, Iran, Himalayas, etc), 1952 (Box-folder 20/4)
    - Latin America: Necessity for Economic and Social Change in Latin America, Undated (Box-folder 20/5)
    - Writings: Politics, 1931-1956 (Box-folder 20/6)
    - Press Conferences, 3/25/1975 (Box-folder 20/7)
    - News Paper Clippings: "Interfaith Group Elects Protestant Co-Chairman", "Douglas Spurs Lawyers", Undated (Box-folder 20/8)
    - Itineraries, Undated (Box-folder 20/9)
    - Misc., Undated (Box-folder 20/10)
    - Conservation, Undated (Box-folder 20/11)
    - Foundations: Roads-to-Peace Committee, 1957 (Box-folder 20/12)
    - Biographical Sketches, Undated (Box-folder 20/13)
    - Address Lists, Undated (Box-folder 20/14)
    - Colleges, Undated (Box-folder 20/15)
    - Albert Parvin Foundation, Undated (Box-folder 20/16)
    - Publishing (Book) Contracts, Undated (Box-folder 20/17)
    - Instruments of Gift, Agreement, of Deposits to Library of Congress, Undated (Box-folder 20/18)
    - Supreme Court Cases and Decisions, Undated (Box-folder 20/19)
    - Yale, 1930 (Box-folder 20/20)
    - Columbia Law School Final Exam, 1927 (Box-folder 20/21)
    - W.O.D. Law Practice, 1926 (Box-folder 20/22)
    - Supreme Court Misc., Undated (Box-folder 20/23)
    - W.O.D. Misc., Undated (Box-folder 20/24)
  - General Correspondence, 1922-1977; Sub-Series 5
    - Christmas Card From Emily; From O.W. Holmes, To Richard K. Stevens, Esq.(2 Copies), 1922-1926 (Box-folder 10/1)
    - Photocopy of 5 Articles Regarding Yale Law School's Clinic on Bankruptcy, 11-Nov-29 (Box-folder 10/2)
    - Letter From W.O.D. to The Banking Commissioner of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, 21-Nov-31 (Box-folder 10/3)
    - Memorandum for Dean Clark: Legal Bibliography Professional Practices (3 Copies)/ Devlp't of Business Units, 1930-32 (Box-folder 10/4)
    - From C.E.C. To Committee on the Curriculum/ From E.M.B. to the Dean (2 Copies), 1933 (Box-folder 10/5)
    - "The Plot Against Wallace", I. F. Stone: Article, 6-Jun-34 (Box-folder 10/6)
    - "Legal Accountaing Business Management the Law"/ Memorandum To": W. W. Werntz, Wm. O. Douglas, Undated (Box-folder 10/7)
    - From Edith Waters, Secretary to Mr. Douglas, To Kristian Falkenberg. Two Letters, Undated (Box-folder 10/8)
    - Misc. correspondence / Report Card Term/ "Integration Of Public Utility Systems"/Photocopy of Knights of the Road/ Hoboes of America Membership Material, 1939 (Box-folder 10/9)
    - Misc. correspondence: Personal and Business/ Library of Congress Book Return Letter, 1940 (Box-folder 10/10)